<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alice Stears</title>
    <link>https://aestears.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alice Stears</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aestears.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>plantTracker</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/package/</guid>
      <description>plantTracker is an R package to transform fine-scale maps of plant occurrence into demographic data that can be used for further analysis. You can find a lot more information about plantTracker here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>I am broadly interested in understanding how environmental variation determines where and when plants exists. I am particularly curious about how species&amp;rsquo; traits mediate the impact of climate variation on plant growth, survival, and reproduction (i.e fitness). Are certain morphological and or physiological characteristics important for predicting plant fitness in every setting? Or do different traits drive fitness differently in habitats with different limiting resources?
Trait-mediated demographic response to drought in the Colorado shortgrass steppe Read more about this project here, in our paper published in Ecology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website in Progress</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/blog/buildingmessage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/blog/buildingmessage/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on building this page, so apologies for the lack of content! Check back for a more complete version soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Postdoctoral research associate at the University of Wyoming as part of both the Weiss-Lehman lab group and the Modelscape collaborative. I also recieved my PhD in Ecology from the University of Wyoming in the Program in Ecology and the Botany Department, where I worked with Dr. Daniel Laughlin. I&amp;rsquo;m a plant ecologist excited about all sorts of questions, but am particularly interested in the impact of global change on the ecological processes that shape plant populations and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/fun/</guid>
      <description>Science is, of course, fun, but I also enjoy a lot of other pursuits. I also think it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important to acknowledge that doing science is a job, and even if it is fulfilling and interesting, it&amp;rsquo;s so valuable and necessary to celebrate and prioritize the other elements of our lives as well.
This page includes links and information about various non-science topics. I hope you find something interesting, useful, or entertaining!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
