<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alice Stears </title>
    <link>https://aestears.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alice Stears </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aestears.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demographic mechansims of persistence for the rare monocarpic perennial *Oenothera coloradensis*</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/project/cobp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/project/cobp/</guid>
      <description>The persistence of naturally rare species has long been a motivating question for ecologists. Classical theory implies that community dynamics should be driven by common species, and that natural selection should not allow small populations of rare species to persist over long periods. And yet, a majority of the species found on earth are rare. Rare species contribute to diversity, community stability, and ecosystem function, and several mechanisms have been proposed to explain their persistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trait-mediated demographic response to drought in the Colorado shortgrass steppe</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/project/co-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/project/co-traits/</guid>
      <description>A major goal in ecology is to make generalizable predictions of organism responses to environmental variation based on their traits. However, straightforward relationships between traits and fitness are rare and likely vary with environmental context. Characterizing how traits mediate demographic responses to the environment may enhance predictions of organism responses to global change.
In this project, we synthesized 15 years of demographic data and species-level traits in a shortgrass steppe to determine whether the effects of leaf and root traits on growth and survival depend on seasonal water availability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
