<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publications on Alice Stears </title>
    <link>https://aestears.github.io/categories/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in publications on Alice Stears </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aestears.github.io/categories/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trait-mediated demographic response to drought in the Colorado shortgrass steppe</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/project/co-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/project/co-traits/</guid>
      <description>A major goal in ecology is to make generalizable predictions of organism responses to environmental variation based on their traits. However, straightforward relationships between traits and fitness are rare and likely vary with environmental context. Characterizing how traits mediate demographic responses to the environment may enhance predictions of organism responses to global change.
In this project, we synthesized 15 years of demographic data and species-level traits in a shortgrass steppe to determine whether the effects of leaf and root traits on growth and survival depend on seasonal water availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Overleaf as a Scientific Collaborator</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/blog/overleaf_forcollab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/blog/overleaf_forcollab/</guid>
      <description>Overleaf 101 Overleaf is an online LaTeX editor that has a lot of great features including simultaneous editing by multiple authors, simple commenting and track changes, and excellent built-in version control. It is a bit different than Microsoft Word or Google Docs, but not by much! Here is a quick overview to help you figure out how (and why) to navigate and contribute to documents written on Overleaf.
Overleaf is LaTeX editor that is hosted online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plantTracker is published on CRAN!</title>
      <link>https://aestears.github.io/blog/planttracker-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestears.github.io/blog/planttracker-live/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Here! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share that plantTracker, an R package that I created as part of my PhD dissertation, is available to download from CRAN!
plantTracker provides several user-friendly functions that extract growth, survival, and competition information from repeatedly-sampled, fine-scale maps of organism occurence. We created these functions specifically to get competition and demographic data from repeatedly-mapped quadrats of perennial plants, but are excited for folks to come up with all sorts of creative applications for these functions!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
